colesclassroom.com 2019-12-24

# Privacy Policy - Cole's Classroom

**Cole’s Classroom Privacy Policy**

colesclassroom.com is serious about protecting your online privacy. This Privacy Statement explains our views and practices concerning privacy, and how they may pertain to you as a user of our website.

You or Your means you as a participant in or as a user of the colesclassroom.com website. We or Our or Us means colesclassroom.com. Our site means colesclassroom.com.

**COLLECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We collect the following categories of Personal Data about you when you use or otherwise interact with our site or choose to purchase our products:

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Home/work/mobile telephone number
  * Billing address
  * Credit/debit card information
  * IP addresses and other information collected passively, as further detailed in the “Passive Collection” section below
  * Device identifiers (mobile vs desktop)

We collect and/or process your Personal Data in connection with the below activities related to our website and products:

  * Placing transactions or orders
  * Registering to attend a webinar
  * Billing and collecting payments for our Products
  * Registering for newsletter subscriptions

**PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will use your Personal Data only in accordance with our Privacy Policy. If you do not wish us to continue using your Personal Data in this manner, you can request that your account be deactivated by contacting us as specified in the “Contact Us” section.

We will only process your Personal Data if we have a lawful basis for doing so. Lawful bases for processing include consent, contractual necessity (i.e. processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract with you, such as your user agreement with us that allows us to provide you with the Products) and our “legitimate interests” or the legitimate interest of others (e.g. our users) such as:

  * Personalizing, improving or operating our Products and business
  * Better understanding your needs and interests
  * Fulfilling requests you make related to the Products
  * Providing you with information and offers from us or third parties
  * Complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes with users, enforcing our agreements
  * Protecting, investigating and deterring against fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized or illegal activity

We process Personal Data for purposes such as:

  * To process your orders and deliver the Products that you have ordered
  * To keep you up to date on the latest Cole’s Classroom news, free tutorials and product announcements
  * To provide support and assistance for our Products
  * To provide the ability to create personal profile areas and view protected content
  * To provide the ability to contact you and provide you with shipping and billing information
  * To provide customer feedback and support
  * To the extent you choose to participate, to conduct questionnaires and surveys in order to provide better products and services to our customers and end users
  * To personalize marketing communications and website content based on your preferences, such as in response to your request for specific information on products and services that may be of interest
  * To meet contract or legal obligations

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION?**

When you purchase something from our site, as part of the buying and selling process, we collect the personal information you give us such as your name, address and email address. This enables us to both fulfill and support the products you purchase.

When you browse our site, we also automatically receive your computer’s internet protocol (IP) address in order to provide us with information that helps us learn about your browser and operating system so we can better improve the experience for all our users.

Email marketing: With your permission, we may send you emails about new products, free and premium content (i.e. blog posts, YouTube videos, reports/whitepapers, etc.), and special events.

**CONSENT**

When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order, arrange for a delivery or return a purchase, we imply that you consent to our collecting it and using it for that specific reason only.

If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason (i.e. newsletter subscription and marketing messages), we will ask you directly for your expressed consent and provide you with an opportunity to withdraw your consent.

You may withdraw your consent at any time by clicking on an “unsubscribe” link which is offered at the bottom of every email we send.

You may also withdraw your consent anytime, by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**DATA SUBJECT RIGHTS**

You have certain rights with respect to your Personal Data as set forth below. Please note that in some circumstances, we may not be able to fully comply with your requests, or we may ask you to provide us with additional information in connection with your request, which may be Personal Data, for example, if we need to verify your identity or the nature of your request. In such situations, however, we will still respond to let you know of our decision.

To make any of the following requests, contact us using the contact details referred to in the “Contact Us” section of this policy.

  * **Access:** You can request more information about the Personal Data we hold about you. You can also request a copy of the Personal Data.
  * **Rectification:** If you believe that any Personal Data we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request that we correct or supplement such data.
  * **Objection:** You can contact us to let us know that you object to the collection or use of your Personal Data for certain purposes.
  * **Erasure:** You can request that we erase some or all of your Personal Data from our systems.
  * **Restriction of Processing:** You can ask us to restrict further processing of your Personal Data.
  * **Withdrawal of Consent:** If we are processing your Personal Data based on your consent (as indicated at the time of collection of such data), you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note, however, that if you exercise this right, you may have to then provide express consent on a case-by-case basis for the use or disclosure of certain of your Personal Data, if such use or disclosure is necessary to enable you to utilize some or all of our Products.

**DATA RETENTION**

How long we retain your Personal Data depends on the type of data and the purpose for which we process the data.

**DISCLOSURE**

We may disclose your personal information if we are required by law to do so or if you violate our Terms of Service. Also, if our site is acquired or merged with another company, your information may be transferred to the new owners so that they may continue to sell and support our products and services.

IMPORTANT: We do not sell, rent or otherwise disclose your personal information to any third parties, including but not limited to advertisers, strategic partners or vendors. Again, we take your privacy very seriously.

**DATA STORAGE**

Our shopping cart solution is hosted and managed by Infusionsoft. They provide us with the online e-commerce platform that allows us to sell our products and services to you.

Your data is stored through Infusionsoft’s data storage, databases and the general Infusionsoft application. They store your data on a secure server behind a firewall.

Payment:

If you choose a direct payment gateway to complete your purchase, then Infusionsoft stores your credit card data. It is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is stored only as long as is necessary to complete your purchase transaction. After that is complete, your purchase transaction information is deleted.

All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover.

PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of credit card information by our store and its service providers.

NOTE: At no point during the transaction does Cole’s Classroom take custody or store your credit card information. This is process is monitored and managed by Infusionsoft, and you can read their terms of service, privacy policy and PCI Compliance information by visiting their site at: <http://www.infusionsoft.com/legal>[  
](http://www.infusionsoft.com/legal)  
**THIRD-PARTY SERVICES**

In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us.

However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.

For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers.

In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.

As an example, if you are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the United States, then your personal information used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.

Once you leave our store’s website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s Terms of Service.

Links: When you click on links on our website, they may direct you away from our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements.

**SECURITY**

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.

If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

**COOKIES**

Cole’s Classroom utilizes cookies to create a more customized experience for our users and customers. For example, we use a login cookie so members do not have to re-enter their username and password each time they return to our site We also use tracking pixels (i.e. Google Analytics) to aid in measuring and tracking where our website traffic is coming from and to track the performance of our site. Finally, we use remarking pixels from Facebook and Google to aid in customized, targeted followup advertising.

**AGE OF CONSENT**

By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this site.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

**CONTACT US**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, [please contact us](https://www.colesclassroom.com/contact/).
